Profile Associate SQA Engineer with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Engineering and over 2 years of experience in Norton LifeLock, a leading cyber security company. With a strong

academic background and a proven track record of delivering success while performing outside of comfort zone, I'm seeking to gain knowledge, exposure and expand my horizons by pursuing a Master's degree and refine my skills.

Dr. M.G.R. Educational and Research Institute, Chennai

Education

B.E in Computer Science and Engineering – GPA: 9.0

2016-2020

Balalok Matric Higher Secondary School, Chennai 2015

Class XII – 91.4%

Work Experience

Seema Modern Matriculation School, Chennai

Class X - 92% 2013

Associate SQA Analyst

Norton LifeLock Software Services India Pvt Ltd, Chennai Oct 2020 – Present

- -Accountable for improving product quality through performing various testing techniques like functional testing, system testing, integration testing, regression testing, sanity, and ad hoc testing.
- -Implementation of Test Automation Framework build using Selenium Web Driver, to handle industry leading harness design patterns and approaches.
- -Create and maintain automation scripts to minimize time and effort involved in quality assurance activities.
- -Collaborate cross-functionally to gather scope information, manage test strategy, escalate issues, and identify risks to mitigate through planning and execution phases.
- -Plan, prepare, execute, and review various testcases to identify product bugs and verify upon fixes implemented.
- -Responsible for analysing test results and providing performance test reports with remediation and recommendations.
- -Worked with Cross Browser Testing across multiple OS to check for compatibility.
- -Ensure on time delivery of product with highest quality.
- -Document and maintain monthly Norton Security product release information.



LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikit a-singh-490909176/ Mansarovar Flats, Iyyapanthangal, Chennai - 56

Nikita.aks98@gmail.com

+91 -6374930532

Nikita Singh

Projects Mobile Automation Norton LifeLock | December 2022-March 2023

Overview: Developing new automation scripts from scratch for Norton Security Mobile products in Android platform using Appium framework.

Contributions:

- Automated Mobile App testcases for different workflows in Android platform using Appium with TestNG and integrated with Jenkins to increase the efficiency of testing the products prior to release.

Software Used: Eclipse – Java with maven Selenium

Appium

SOS Two Click Refresh Norton LifeLock | April 2021 - September 2021

Overview: The objective of this project was to entirely automate Norton LifeLock's Partner products in Windows Platform as per the requirements for every new release, starting with the Request form creation till the object that contains configuration for every partner to download the product through the URLs.

Contributions:

- Developed and implemented REST API's scripts and including JSON data formats and API visioning strategy.
- Worked on distributed test automation execution on different environment as a part of continuous integration process using Jenkins.

Software Used: Visual Studio Code-Python

Postman-RESTAPI& Jenkins

Dark Web Monitoring (DWM) Norton LifeLock | November 2020-Feb 2021

Overview: Dark web monitoring is a service that scans and notifies the user if their personal information is detected on dark

websites and forums in order to expose identity theft and other crime activities.

Contributions:

- Created and added the required sets in the internal tools of Norton LifeLock to support the DWM feature.
- Validated and ensured that the feature is working fine across all platforms and regions.
- Updated the automation test scripts to ensure currency.

Software Used: Visual Studio Code-Python Postman-API

Drone Assisted Damage Relief Final Year | July 2019

Overview: Usage of UAV in disasters to know the extent of the damage and identify victims in the inaccessible locations to rescue them with the help of Machine Learning technologies like Deep Learning and Image processing.

Technology Used: Deep Learning - YOLO Face Recognition Image Processing

Software Used: Android Studio- Python

Development Boards: Arduino

Raspberrypi

Contributions

- Trained models for object detection.
- Building an Android application.
- Applied Image pre-processing techniques

Decentralized VPN Third Year | October 2018

Overview: Researched on how to build a blockchain powered Decentralized VPN that will overcome the cons of the current centralized VPN to provide better security and privacy of the user's data.

Technology Used: Ethereum Blockchain

Smart contracts Decentralization

Certifications Python	2020
Machine Learning and Data Science	2020
International Software Testing Qualification Board (ISTQB) –Foundation Leve	el 2020
Java	2019
Data Structures and Algorithms	2019

- -Presented a session on Space Decentralization (A Decentralized VPN to improve privacy and security of data) at Ravensbourne University London, organized and sponsored by Mozfest'18.
- -Led and drove multiple national and international university events like Techastra'19, Techastra'20, Litfest'19 and Glitecrazzy'19.
- -Organized various technical and non-technical student activities for the department and professional societies.

Achievements -Submitted an idea on "An approach towards Queer inclusive AI" (using Machine Learning Algorithms to make AI more inclusive to queer people) which was selected at Mozfest'19.

-Selected to present research paper on "Drone Assisted Damage Relief" at a National level

-Featured in University magazines and social media for technical articles and blogs.

C

Python Java SQL

Machine Learning

Communication & Presentation Skills Teamwork & Collaboration

Operating System – Windows, Mac, Linux

Database – Oracle (SQL)

 $\boldsymbol{IDE-Jupyter,\,VScode}$

Applications

Skills

Database Management- Confluence. Repository Management- Perforce.

Manual- JIRA, TORO

Automation- Selenium (Framework), Ranorex, Jenkins